<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>healthcare on diogo carapito</title>
    <link>https://diogocarapito.com/tags/healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in healthcare on diogo carapito</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:10:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diogocarapito.com/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Medical Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/6_medical_llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/6_medical_llms/</guid>
      <description>I attended last week the Medical Large Language Models for Clinical Text Summarization, Information Extraction, and Question Answering from John Snow Labs. I&amp;rsquo;m sharing my notes here.
LLMs LLMs and NLP in general are providing new tools to solve existing problems in healthcare. Here is a list of some new tools that are available today:
Question Answering Text Summarization Text Generation Information extraction (e.g. from clinical notes) Relation extraction (e.g. symptoms related to a disease) Entity recognition (like ICD-10 code extraction) Chatbots Many open source LLMs available today have close performance to the best commercial state-of-the-art models, like GPT-4, GPT-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mgfhub.com is now live!</title>
      <link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/4_mgfhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:41:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/4_mgfhub/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce that mgfhub.com is now live!
It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a search tool with data visualization components for KPIs (&amp;ldquo;indicadores&amp;rdquo;) that exists in Portuguese Primary Care. I have imagined it for more than a year, and it&amp;rsquo;s trying to answer questions that I have in my daily life as a Family Medicine Resident when I&amp;rsquo;m working with KPIs:
How many KPIs exist?
How do KPIs work?
How to quickly find specific KPIs (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Summit Healthcare 2023</title>
      <link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/3_nlp_summit_healtchare_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:18:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/3_nlp_summit_healtchare_2023/</guid>
      <description>This week I attended the NLP Summit Healthcare 2023, a free virtual event organized by the John Snow Labs. It was a great event with a lot of interesting talks. I’ll share some of my key takeaways.
1. Best practices when developing NLP models Presented in the opening keynote by Dr. David Gondek, Chief Data Scientist at John Snow Labs, he sumarized some best practices that i found interesting as I’m beginning my NLP journey:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>webapps and tutorials</title>
      <link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/2_webapps_and_tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:41:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/2_webapps_and_tutorials/</guid>
      <description>This week has been exciting. I have this NLP project cooking inside my head (for some time now) and I’ve been speeding through many youtube tutorials on both backend and frontend structure.
For the backend, I’ve been cruising through Pinecone, LangChain and OpenAI API, thanks to tutorials from James Briggs and Data independent. Google colab has been my best friend.
Even though the backend is the new exciting stuff, I have a sweet spot for the way it’s presented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
