<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Updates on diogo carapito</title><link>https://diogocarapito.com/tags/updates/</link><description>Recent content in Updates on diogo carapito</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:39:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diogocarapito.com/tags/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summer is over! Time to MLOps</title><link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/8_summer_is_over/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:39:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/8_summer_is_over/</guid><description>&lt;p>This summer was &lt;strong>rough&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beguining was going well.
I finished my &lt;a href="https://github.com/DiogoCarapito/predictive_methods_project_nova_ims/">project&lt;/a> for &lt;strong>Predictive Methods of Data Mining&lt;/strong> at &lt;a href="https://www.novaims.unl.pt/">NOVA IMS&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with the results. We ended up used streamlit, and we got a pretty good score on Kaggle with our rather simple neural network. =D&lt;br>
I also watched the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kvxaj6pHeVA">LLM Bootcamp 2023&lt;/a>, which gave me a lot of insight on the current state of LLMs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But my side projects were slowing down.
I guess I was able to picture a structure in my head that might work (front end, backend&amp;rsquo;s data flow, data storage, RAG adn LLM inteerface) but I was having trouble implementing it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>hugo</title><link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/5_hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 11:29:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/5_hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last time I posted a blog post, I almost went nuts to make it work.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember how to publish a post.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it was, maybe guithub pages, maybe the quarto framework, but definitly my dumbness was a big part of it.
I just can&amp;rsquo;t grasp yet &lt;strong>how&lt;/strong> all this &lt;strong>unintuitive git shenanigans work&lt;/strong>.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve been postponing my new blog post, knowing what awaited me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>hello, world!</title><link>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/1_hello_world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 22:18:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://diogocarapito.com/posts/1_hello_world/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been charging into different directions on my journey to build a bridge between health and tech (NLP and LLMs, I’m looking at you).
There is so much potential and I have so many ideas!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, lately I’ve been:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>grinding through &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8SF_h3xF3cE&amp;amp;list=PLfYUBJiXbdtSvpQjSnJJ_PmDQB_VyT5iU">fast.ai Practical Deep Learning for Coders&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> (just finished the 4th lesson this week)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>exploring &lt;strong>website domain name&lt;/strong> stuff and setting up an website of my previous project (Primary care KPIs exploration tool, &lt;strong>&lt;a href="mgfhub.com">mgfhub.com&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reconnecting to social media (I’ve been away for a while now), setting up linkedin, twitter and joining relevant discord servers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>after completing &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.novaims.unl.pt/en/education/programs/postgraduate-programs-and-master-degree-programs/postgraduate-program-in-information-management-and-business-intelligence-in-healthcare/">Postgraduate Program in Information Management and Business Intelligence in Healthcare&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> @NOVA IMS, I felt the need to keep learning about data mining, so i’m doing a single course on Predictive Methods of Data Mining&lt;/li>
&lt;li>exploring DL, ML, NLP and LLM main concepts and recent developments (looking at you &lt;a href="https://www.chatbase.co/">chatbase.co&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.chatpdf.com/">ChatPDF&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://quarto-bot.onrender.com/">Quarto Help Bot&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>trying and failing implementing LLMs with jupyter notebooks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>exploring how to start a blog (thanks fast.ai for the push!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Initially I thought implementing a blog with &lt;strong>Dash&lt;/strong> and publish it on &lt;a href="https://www.pythonanywhere.com/">pythonanywhere.com&lt;/a>, since I’ve worked with Flask in the past months.
But that would take more time to set up something that might be already solved.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>